<dashboard>
  <label>Machine Learning Toolkit</label>
  <description>The Machine Learning Toolkit delivers new SPL commands, custom visualizations, assistants, and examples to explore a variety of machine learning concepts.</description>
  <row>
    <panel>
      <html>
        <h2>Overview</h2>
        <p>The Machine Learning Toolkit delivers new SPL commands, custom visualizations, assistants, and examples to explore a variety of machine learning concepts. Each assistant includes end-to-end examples with datasets, plus the ability to apply the visualizations and SPL commands to your own data. You can inspect the assistant panels and underlying code to see how it all works.</p>
        
        <h3>Splunk Machine Learning Overview Tour</h3>
        <div style="margin-left:30px">
          <iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3uhXdSwOoLM" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true"/>
        </div>
        
        <br/>
        
        <h3>Splunk Machine Learning Toolkit Deep Dive</h3>
        <div style="margin-left:30px">
          <iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/J3hiYGs1H58" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true"/>
        </div>
      </html>
      </panel>
      <panel>
      <html>
        <h3>Features and improvements</h3>
        <ul>
          <li>A <code>streaming_apply</code> setting has been added to the mlspl.conf file, which allows you to run the <code>apply</code> command on your indexers.</li>
          <li>The KernelRidge regression, DecisionTreeClassifier and DecisionTreeRegressor algorithms are now supported.</li>
          <li>The <code>max_features</code> parameter of the RandomForestClassifier and RandomForestRegressor algorithms now accepts values with the float data type.</li>
          <li>The <b>Predict Numeric Fields</b> and <b>Predict Categorical Fields</b> assistants now allow you to enter wildcards in <b>Fields to use for predicting</b>. For example, to specify both the Packets Received and Packets Sent fields, enter "Packets*". Wildcards are case sensitive.</li>
          <li>The <b>Select All</b> and <b>Select None</b> buttons on the <b>Predict Numeric Fields</b> and <b>Predict Categorical Fields</b> assistants have been moved inside the dropdown list.</li>
          <li>The <b>Detect Numeric Outliers</b> assistant now includes an <b>Include current point</b> checkbox to support the "current" parameter of the <code>streamstats</code> command.</li>
          <li>The <b>Predict Numeric Fields</b> assistant has an improved Actual vs. Predicted Line Chart, which replaces the Actual vs. Predicted Overlay.</li>
          <li>Two macros in the <b>Forecast Time Series</b> assistant have been merged into one macro.</li>
          <li>The <b>Remove from history</b> confirmation dialog box has been improved.</li>
          <li>The visualizations in the <b>Cluster Events</b> showcase have been updated.</li>
          <li>A basic framework has been implemented for displaying Bootstrap's modal dialog boxes in the Machine Learning Toolkit UI.</li>
        </ul>
      </html>
    </panel>
  </row>
</dashboard>